## **James Carleton**

# "I love designing **elegant** and **engaging** product experiences for **humans**."

I've been working toward this goal most recently at PayPal Inc. I love working with creative individuals that can bring strong critique as well as laugh at the latest meme. I thrive on the challenge of leading interaction and visual design efforts with product and development staff toward results that meet business and UX goals. I strive to take every opportunity to grow through teammates, trainings, industry events and online resources.

I continually test emerging tools and methods to find the most effective workflow. After years of designing and developing the interwebs, I know my PNGs, PSDs, CLI, Git, IA, UI, UX and UAT. My days are lived in white board sketches, flows, wireframes, mockups, wiki pages, test results, and of course Web Inspector. I admire multi-device strategy, design thinking, user testing, agile dev, and lean UX. I avoid vague meetings, hasty reactions and deadly scope creep.

### Experience

2016 to Present - PayPal Inc. - Sr. User Experience Designer, Design Systems

- Building design system artifacts and processes for use across product teams
- 2011 to 2016 Move Inc./Realtor.com Sr. User Experience Designer, Consumer UX group
  - Lead designer for Realtor.com responsive search results experience project
  - Lead designer for Realtor.com map search redesign
  - Lead designer for Realtor.com pattern library
  - Lead designer for Realtor.com Mortgage iOS/Android mobile app
  - Frequent contributor to UX team design reviews, forums, and design documentation
  - Agile scrum trained, worked closely with developers in agile sprints
  - Integrated user research (qualitative and quantitative) into project process
  - Interaction/animation/motion design prototyping
  - Familiarity with HTML/CSS has increased my capability to collaborate with developers
  - Samples available upon request

## **More Experience**

2010 to 2011 - Tinyprints (a Shutterfly Co.)

- Front End Developer for two booming e-commerce stationery brands: tinyprints.com and weddingpaperdivas.com
- Programmed HTML/CSS for website re-brand, seasonal edits, SEO and marketing emails

1997 to Present - James Carleton Design / E&J Design

 Freelance designer providing design/dev services to a variety of businesses and organizations,

large and small.

- Sold, managed, and delivered a range of consulting services. Later formed E&J Design with expanded staff and service capacity
- I enjoy using side work as a playground to sharpen my skills and explore new approaches and technologies

#### Education

1998 to 2003 - Bachelor of Science: Industrial Design

- San Jose State University
- Scholarship winner, student IDSA member/officer

1996 to 1998 - Associates: Art

Hartnell College

#### More

I like to keep things simple, but can provide more details as needed. Just let me know, thanks!

- Portfolio & Blog: www.carletondesign.com
- Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/jamescarleton
- Email: me@carletondesign.com
- Phone: 408-874-6001

